iii.org 2019-06-24

# Privacy Policy | III

**_Effective Date:    05/11/15_**

Insurance Information Institute takes your privacy seriously.  The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you about how and why we collect and use particular information that is provided by or collected from users of the Insurance Information Institute’s web site (the “Site”) and how your privacy is protected.  As used in this Privacy Policy, “we”, “our” and “us” means the Insurance Information Institute unless otherwise indicated.

**_Modifications to this Privacy Policy_**

**Each time a user accesses this Site, this Privacy Policy should be reviewed because Insurance Information Institute reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time.   Insurance Information Institute will notify you by changing the effective date of this Privacy Policy.  Your use of the site after any such changes constitutes your acceptance of such changes.**

**_Information Collected_**

Insurance Information Institute only collects personally-identifiable information to the extent reasonably necessary for our business purposes.

_Contact Information_

If you choose to contact us, or if you request further information or periodic updates about the Insurance Information Institute, we may request your name, company name, email address and phone number to respond to your request and to provide such information and updates.

_Information Collected through Forms on the Site_

If you fill out a form that will generate and automatically send us an email through the Site, we will ask for your email address, and we may also ask for other information, including your name, company name, phone number and, in some cases, your city and state of residence.  Such information may be used to contact you in response to your submission or to send you information and updates about the Insurance Information Institute and our services.

_Removal from Email_

If you wish to be removed at any time from our email update list, please send an email to [info@iii.org](mailto:info@iii.org) with the word “remove” in the subject field.

_Information Collected by Yahoo! Shopping_

If you make a payment to Insurance Information Institute using Yahoo! Shopping’s online payment system, Yahoo! Shopping may ask you to provide certain information which will be stored and processed by Yahoo! Shopping as necessary to complete your transaction and in accordance with Yahoo! Shopping’s Privacy Policy.  Information that you provide to Yahoo! Shopping will also be forwarded in a notification or report to the Insurance Information Institute.  However, credit card numbers or checking account numbers provided to Yahoo! Shopping are not provided to the Insurance Information Institute.  Any further questions about Yahoo! Shopping are best answered by the information on the Yahoo! Shopping Web site, and we urge you to review Yahoo! Shopping’s Privacy Policy regarding collection and use of personal information by Yahoo! Shopping.  **Insurance Information Institute is not responsible for Yahoo! Shopping’s use or storage of your information.**

_Site Usage Information and Cookies_

We also collect tracking information derived mainly from tallying page views throughout the Site, enabling use to review your activity on the Site in anonymous or aggregated form.  Our Web server automatically recognizes and collects the domain name and IP address of visitors to the Site.  We may use ‘cookies’ to enhance your online experience with the Insurance Information Institute.  A ‘cookie’ is a small file that your Web browser will place on your hard drive or device.  It allows us to remember you and keep track of your preferences and passwords.  Use of cookies allows us to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your password so you don’t have to re-enter it each time you visit the Site.  You can, of course, set your browser to reject cookies – but keep in mind that this may affect your use of the Site.

_Protection of Information_

We use reasonable procedure to protect personally-identifiable information received from users against unauthorized use or disclosure.

**_Use of Information_**

Email addresses and other information provided by users of the Site will be used to respond to your requests and to provide requested information and updates about the Insurance Information Institute and its services.  We may also disclose user personal information provided on the Site as reasonably necessary to respond to or implement the user’s request.  Site-tracking and usage information we collect is used to improve the Site and the Insurance Information Institute services.

_External Distribution of Personally-Identifiable Information_

Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, Insurance Information Institute does not externally distribute personally-identifiable information provided by or collected from our web site users, except if a user, customer or potential customer specifically opts-in that certain of its personally-identifiable information be distributed to a third party.  Third parties may be engaged by the Insurance Information Institute to perform a variety of services and functions, including providing technical and hosting services for the Site. These third parties may have access to your personally-identifiable information if necessary to perform such services and functions; however, they are only authorized to use such personal information for the purpose of performing such services and functions and are not authorized to use your personally-identifiable information for any other purpose.  In addition, Insurance Information Institute may transfer your personally-identifiable information in connection with the sale of Insurance Information Institute’s assets or any of its products or services or in connection with a merger or acquisition of Insurance Information Institute.

_Additional Disclosures_

We also may disclose user personal information to third parties if we reasonably believe that the law requires it, that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, the rights of another user or person, or to prevent harm.  We reserve the right to disclose any personal information as reasonably necessary, in our judgment, to protect the Insurance Information Institute or its assets or to comply with law or with appropriate requests or directions made by law enforcement, government agencies or any court.

**_Third Party Web Sites_**

THE SITE CONTAINS LINKS TO FACILITATE USER ACCESS TO EXTERNAL OR THIRD PARTY SITES (SUCH AS YAHOO! SHOPPING), NONE OF WHICH ARE CONTROLLED OR OFFERED BY THE INSURANCE INFORMATION INSTITUTE.  THEREFORE, THIRD PARTY SITES LINKED FROM THIS SITE ARE NOT SUBJECT TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY.  YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR REVIEWING THE PRIVACY POLICIES OF ANY LINKED THIRD PARTY SITES TO DETERMINE HOW YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION WILL BE COLLECTED, UTILIZED, AND PROTECTED BY SUCH THIRD PARTY SITES.  THE INSURANCE INFORMATION INSTITUTE IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY CONTENT, FEATURES, OR ACTIVITIES OF ANY LINKED THIRD PARTY SITES (INCLUDING THEIR PRIVACY PRACTICES), AND THE INSURANCE INFORMATION INSTITUTE DISCLAIMS ANY AND ALL RESPONSIBILITY AND/OR LIABILITY FOR THE CONTENTS, FEATURES, AND ACTIVITIES, AND THE COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION BY SUCH THIRD PARTY SITES.

**_Contacting the Insurance Information Institute_**

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with the Site, you can contact us at: [info@iii.org](mailto:info@iii.org) or by writing to us at the address below.  We are always glad to hear from you.

Insurance Information Institute  
110 William Street  
New York, New York 10038

_**Binding Agreement;** **Applicable Laws, Jurisdiction and Waivers**_

Any user that accesses all or any party of this Site agrees that such user is at least eighteen (18) years old and that such user has consented to this Privacy Policy.  Any claims arising out of or relating to this Privacy Policy or the privacy or use of users’ information shall be governed by the laws of the State of New York, U.S.A., without giving effect to any conflicts of laws provisions.  You agree that in the event of any dispute or claim with respect to this Privacy Policy or the privacy or use of your information, the sole and exclusive jurisdiction for bringing any such action shall be in the courts located in the Borough of Manhattan in New York City, New York, and you waive any and all rights to claim inconvenient forum or immunity.  **Each** **user waives any and all rights to a jury trial with respect to any claim arising out of or relating to** **this Privacy Policy or the privacy or use of such user’s information**.
